The Hare and the Tortoise.
A Hare was one day making fun of a
Tortoise for being so slow upon his feet.
"Wait a bit," said the Tortoise;
"I'll run a race with you,
and I'll wager that I win." "Oh, well,"
replied the Hare, who was much amused at
the idea, "let's try and see";
and it was soon agreed that the fox should
set a course for them, and be the judge.
When the time came both started off
together, but the Hare was soon so far
ahead that he thought he might as well
have a rest: so down he lay and fell fast
asleep. Meanwhile the Tortoise kept
plodding on, and in time reached the goal.
At last the Hare woke up with a start,
and dashed on at his fastest,
but only to find that the Tortoise had
already won the race. Slow and steady wins
the race.